Guide to the Tony Martin Papers 1960-2006 MSS 190
© 2009 Fales Library and Special Collections
Tony Martin Papers
1960-2006
MSS 190
© 2009 Fales Library and Special Collections
5.67 Linear feet (5 boxes)
The Tony Martin Papers document Martin's career as a multimedia artist. Martin was one of the first artists to use light as an artistic medium. A recipient of a National Endowment for the Arts Individual Artist Fellowship, Martin has worked regularly with such composers as Pauline Oliveros, Morton Subotnick and David Tudor. The Papers include correspondence, sketches, announcements and other documents pertaining to Martin's artistic production and exhibitions. They also include video and film that was used in Martin's artworks, as well as video documentation of performances.
Martin, Tony, 1937 -
Provenance
The Tony Martin Papers were donated to Fales Library by Tony Martin in 2006.
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival materials.
Biographical Note
Tony Martin was born in Knoxville, Tennessee in 1937. He studied at the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor and The Art Institute of Chicago. A painter from the outset, Martin is one of the first artists to use light as a medium, often incorporating light compositions and visual projections into musical performances and interactive installations. He is a recipient of a National Endowment for the Arts Individual Artist Fellowship, and has worked regularly with such composers as Pauline Oliveros, Morton Subotnick and David Tudor.
Martin makes works that engage the viewer as a participant. This interest in interactivity began in 1962 with his first multisensory environmental piece, "Theater For Walkers, Talkers, Touchers" (1962); this work, as well as current works, apply principles of resonance and feedback through photo and proximity electronics. Martin has collaborated with David Tudor for the Merce Cunningham Dance Company, created work for the E.A.T. Pepsi Pavilion at Expo 70, in Osaka, Japan, and has exhibited his work at galleries and museums worldwide.
In 1993, Martin helped co-found The Painting Center, with the aim of providing exhibition space to both emerging and mature painters pursuing various formal directions.
Sources:
- http://www.tonymartin.us/index.html
One and Two Person Exhibitions
2009 Mills Music Festival, two performances: "Sound.Light.Migrations",'09 with Pauline Oliveros, "Desert Ambulance",'63 with Ramon Sender
2009 "Light Pendulum" an interactive light sculpture commissioned for 103point9wavefarm, Catskill, NY
2008 Miami-Basel Artfair: Multiprojector performance sponsored by PS1
2009 Art Students League, NYC and Vytlacil Center: performances Art and Music
2006 Mills College, Oakland, CA, Songlines Series Visual Compositions
2005 James Madison University, Sawhill Gallery, Harrisburg, VA Galaxy
2003 Sideshow Gallery, Brooklyn, NY Visual Poetry In Light In Time
2002 Electronic Arts Intermix, New York, NY Artists’ Web Projects Launch Galaxy - work for the Web
2002 Roxbury Arts Group, Roxbury, NY The Light In Between, one person show
2002 Studio 18 Gallery, New York, NY Tony Martin/Bendel Hydes
2000 Los Angles County Museum of Art San Francisco Tape Center, retrosp.
1998 Simon Gallery, Morristown, NJ Tony Martin: Paintings
1996 salon Catherine Kessedjian, The Hague, Netherlands Tony Martin new work
1996 Myung Sook Lee Gallery, New York, NY November To November: A Year
1995 The Painting Center, New York, NY
1995 Cyr Center Gallery, Stamford, NY Tony Martin: Paintings, works on paper 1994
1994 The Painting Center, NYC, one person exhibition
1991 Scott Alan Gallery, New York, NY Tony Martin/Paul Sierra
1990 Scott Alan Gallery, New York, NY Tony Martin: Works On Paper
1981 The Katonah Gallery, Katonah, NY Art Of Reaction
1980 Institute for Art and Urban Resources, P.S. 1, Long Island City, NY
1974 Princeton University, Princeton, NJ
1974 Light Composition for Merce Cunningham, New York, NY
1971 Cooper Union Gallery, New York, NY, "Spectral Time Tide"
1970 Howard Wise Gallery, New York, NY
1969 Whitney Museum, New York, NY Sight And Sound, Light Cook-assisted by Bill Sward, compositions with Mel Powell and Jean Erdman
1968,1969 - Howard Wise Gallery, New York, NY one person exhibitions The Gameroom (docu.-BBC), The Well, Door, You Me We, Column. These are all viewer-participatory, interactive sculptures and installations now in permanent collections of The Everson Museum, Syracuse, NY and The Butler Institute of American Art, Youngstown, NY
1967 Museum of Modern Art, New York, NY Electronic Chamber
1963 Batman Gallery, San Francisco, CA Paintings: Anthony Martin
1962 San Francisco Museum of Art, San Francisco, CA
Group Exhibitions
2007 Far Fields, Treadwell, NY Variations: Dark and Light
2007 Whitney Museum of American Art, New York, NY Summer Of Love
2007 The ‘temporary Museum Of Art, Brooklyn, NY
2007 Holland Tunnel, Brooklyn, NY Art Club Jazz
2006 Leubsdorf Art Gallery at Hunter College, New York, NY To Shanghai And Back
2006 The Painting Center New York, NY 13th Anniversary Show
2006 Museum Of The City Of New York, New York, NY Light Transforms The Night
2006 Rotterdam Film Festival, Rotterdam, The Netherlands, Legendary Light Shows
2005 Seoul, Korea Film Festival, Five Stanzas
2005 National Academy Invitational, National Academy Museum, New York, NY 179th Annual Invitational Exhibition (catalogue)
2004 EMPAC at RPI, Troy, NY Wow and Flutter (SFMTC compositions and Silent Light) 2003 Studio 18 Gallery New York, NY Flow: From The Bottom Up
2002 Eyebeam Atelier, New York, NY Beta Launch
2001 Palm Beach Institute of Contemporary Art, Palm Beach FL Brooklyn! (catalogue)
2001 New York Studio School, New York Painting Abstraction II
2001 to present - Catskill Rural Aids Society, Roxbury, NY Annual Art For Life Auction
2000 Musee d’Art Moderne de la Ville de Paris, France
1999 De Nederlandsche Bank, Amsterdam, The Netherlands New Tide: Dutch and American Painters
1999 Westbeth Gallery, New York, NY The Power Of Drawing
1999 76 Varick New York, NY (Four person exhibition)
1998 The Gallery on the Hudson, Irvington, NY Looking For The Light
1998 Williamsburg Art & Historical Center, Brooklyn, NY New Tide: Dutch & American Painters (catalogue)
1998 Art Actual, Aula De Lletres, Barcelona, Spain
1997 Brooklyn Museum, Brooklyn, NY Works from Pierogi Gallery Flat Files also: Gasworks (London) and The Corner House (Manchester) England
1996 Art Initiatives, New York, NY Appraising Abstraction
1995 PSA Art Showcase Public Securities Association, New York, NY Continuity And Change (catalogue)
1994 The Gallery at Kohn Pedersen Fox, New York, NY also: The Gallery at Hastings On Hudson, Hastings-on-Hudson, NY Abstract Expressionism: An Ongoing Legacy
1993 E.S. Vandam Gallery, New York, NY Presence And Absence The Painting Center, New York, NY The Preview Show
1992 Scott Alan Fine Arts New York, NY Abstractus: Recent Works
1991 Stephen Rosenberg Gallery, New York, NY Paper Trail
1989 Anita Shapolsky Gallery, New York, NY Architecture As Abstraction (catalogue)
1988 San Francisco Tape Music Center Retrospective, Victoria Theater, San Francisco
1986 University Of Shanghai, China Approaches To Abstraction (catalogue)
1986 Brooklyn Museum Of Art Brooklyn '86 (catalogue)
1983 Institute for Art & Urban Resources, P.S.1, Long Island City, NY
1982 Institute for Art & Urban Resources, P.S.1 Long Island City, NY
1978 Huntsville Museum of Art, Huntsville, AL Art Of The Space Era (catalogue)
1977 Art Institute of Chicago, Chicago, IL Centennial Exhibition (catalogue)
1977 Max Protetch Gallery, Washington, DC
1975 James Yu Gallery, New York, NY Kinaesthetics 1975
1974 Longridge Mall, Rochester, NY 3 interactive sculptures
1970 Expo 70, Osaka, Japan Experiments In Art and Technology Pepsi Pavilion
1968 Milwaukee Arts Center, Milwaukee, WI Options (catalogue)- The Gameroom
1968 Chicago Museum of Contemporary Art, Chicago, Il. – The Gameroom
Fellowships and Grants
1991 PSC-CUNY Award
1979 NYSCA
1972 NEA Individual Artist Fellowship
1970 Creative Artist Public Service Grant
Public Collections
Arkansas Arts Center, Little Rock, AK
Bayshore Museum, Queensborough Community College, Queens, NY
Butler Institute of American Art, Youngstown, OH
Evergreen International Spot Trading, New York, NY
Everson Museum, Syracuse, NY
The Fales Library and Special Collections, New York University, NY (Anthony Martin Papers)
Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden
Kingsborough Community College, Brooklyn, NY
University of Indiana, Bloomington, IN
Selected Private Collections
Robert Bly, Minneapolis, MN
Marshal Beil, New York, NY
Max Hutchinson and Marion Kaselle, North Branch, NY
Marjorie Kellogg, Sydney, NY
Catherine Kessedjian, Paris, France
Mr. and Mrs. Walter Landor, San Francisco, CA
Joan La Barbara & Morton Subotnick, New York, NY
Lectures and Interviews
2007 EAT - Julie Martin (2 interviews)
2006 Fales Annual Lecture - John Hanhardt, Curator of Film and Video at the Guggenheim re: Tony Martin and other artists
2006 BBC London - Interview with Tony Martin for Norman Granz documentary (re: Granz & artist's father, illustrator David Stone Martin)
2005 The Artists Archive - Tony Martin interviewed in his Brooklyn studio by Robert DiMaro - Dec. 1, 2005
2004 Tony Martin interviewed by Cort Worthington (re: Eyebeam) Feb. 2004
2003 Brown Bag Lectures at The Roger Williams Hotel - Martin on his own work Baruch Smucker Elysian Fields - Tom Welsh
Mode Records - Tony and Morton Subotnick
2001 New York Studio School, New York, NY Evening Lecture Series (April 24th) "Tools For The Spirit" - lecture by Martin on his work
1968 BBC film - Howard Wise Gallery exhibition "The Gameroom"
New Publication - www.ucpress.edu/books/pages/10623.html
Selected Bibliography
Alloway, Lawrence, Options Milwaukee Arts Center, 1968 Exhibition catalogue
Brougher, Kerry, Visual Music, Hirshhorn Museum - MOCA-LA ,2005
Bernstein, David W., editor The San Francisco Tape Music Center: 60's Counterculture and The Avant Garde University Of California Press, 2008 (DVD included)
Chadabe, Joel, Electric Sound: The Past and Promise of Electronic Music Prentice Hall, 1996
Edelman, Robert G., Art In America p.104 December 1994
Eshoo, Amy, editor 560 Broadway: A New York Drawing Collection at Work, 1991 - 2006 Fifth Floor Foundation in association with Yale University Press, New Haven and London, 2007
Farrington, Margot Flares and Fathoms Bright Hill Press, 2005 (poetry collection, front cover)
Frank, Peter, L.A. Weekly December 21, 2000 p.46
Gordon, Alastair Spaced Out, Rizzoli, 2008
Henken, John, “Sound/Light Manipulations From "60's Still Pack Power"
Los Angeles Times p. F4 December 13, 2000
Hoodock, Jeff “Interactive Art Offers Surprisingly Human Feel” Daily News Record Harrisburg, VA
Kessedjian, Catherine, The Art I Love Paris, France (book)
Kranz, Stewart Science And Technology In The Arts, Van Nostrand Reinhold, 1974
Pearlman, Ellen "Breakthroughs In Light: The Work Of Tony Martin" The Brooklyn Rail p. 24 March/April 2002
Raynor, Vivien, "Technology As A Medium For Artists" New York Times, Feb. 22 Renan, Sheldon The American Underground Film, Dutton, 1967
Richardson, Derk "Avant Experiments" San Francisco Bay Guardian, p. 49 and 52 June 12 - 18 1996
Rogers, Bertha Out Of The Catskills And Just Beyond Bright Hill Press p. 124 - 25 (literary anthology with reproductions of two works)
Rose, Barbara, Pavilion, Dutton, NY 1972
Sanford, Mariellen R. Happenings and Other Acts Routledge, NY, 1995
Schwartz, Barry The New Humanism: Art In A Time Of Change, Praeger, NY 1974
Tisano, Teresa Sauer, editor Notations 21, Mark Batty, 2008 (front cover ,visual scores)
Tompkins, Calvin "Onward and Upward With The Arts" The New Yorker, NY 1970
Zimmer, William "Abstract Expressionism Is Alive And Well" New York Times p. 18, November 27, 1994
Webwork - http://www.eai.org/eai/title.htm?id=7609
Works on DVD/Film/Tape
Mode Records (SideWinder/Until Spring)
Performance at Mills College for Songlines Series - recorded Nov. 16th, 2006
Wow & Flutter Festival - EMPAC 2004
Victoria Theater SF, Ca. 1986 Retrospective
Center For Visual Music, LA,Ca. (archives)
Baltimore, Rotterdam, Seoul - Film and Video Festivals
Scope and Content Note
The Tony Martin Papers consist of five series, including one oversize series.
SERIES I: Documentary and Graphic Material is subdivided into five subseries documenting different aspects of Tony Martin's artistic career, as well as his corresondence with notable artists and art organizations. Material in Subseries A through C is arranged chronologically, while material in Subseries D and E is arranged alphabetically.
Subseries A: Exhibitions
Subseries B: Visual Compositons, Performance
Subseries C: Intervactive Sculptures
Subseries D: Sketches, Notes and Miscellaneous
Subseries E: Correspondence
SERIES II: Book Collection is housed in the Fales Library. The books have been catalogued in Bobcat. A keyword or related name search with the name "Tony Martin" will retrieve the records for the books. See "separated materials" for a list of the books.
SERIES III: Media is divided into four subseries:
Subseries A: Video Recordings - Access Copies
Subseries B: Video Recordings - Originals
Subseries C: Film - Access Copies
Subseries D: Film - Originals
Subseries A and C are access copies available to researchers use by request.
SERIES IV: Objects contains electronic circuitry used in Martin's interactive sculptures.
OVERSIZE SERIES contains oversize documentary and graphic material. Some entries are cross-listed with entries in Series I.
Separated Materials
Selected printed materials have been removed and individually catalogued in the Downtown Collection. Records for these items can be retrieved through Bobcat.
Chadabe, Joel. Electric Sound: The Past and Promise of Electronic Music. New Jersey: Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1997.
Kluver, Billy, et al., Ed. Pavilion: by Experiments in Art and Technology. New York: E.P. Dutton & Co., Inc., 1972.
Renen, Sheldon. An Introduction to the American Underground Film. New York: E.P. Dutton & Co., Inc., 1967.
Sandford, Mariellen R., Ed. Happenings and Other Acts. London: Routledge, 1995.
Oliveros, Pauline, 1932-; Paik, Nam June; Wise, Howard; Experiments in Art and Technology (Organization); Interactive art
- Series I: Documentary and Graphic Material
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains invitations, announcements, catalogues and other material relating to Tony Martin's one-person and group painting exhibitions. The material is arranged chronologically.
  - Subseries A: Exhibitions
    - OPTIONS (with essay on Game Room) - The Museum of Contemporary Art, Chicago, IL & The Milwaukee Art Center, WI, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Affect / Effect - La Jolla Museum of Art, La Jolla, CA, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Expo 70, "Experiments in Art & Technology" - Pepsi Pavillion, Osaka, Japan, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Art of the Space Era (catalogue) - Huntsville Museum of Art, Huntsville, AL, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Anthony Martin - Vector Image Series - Institute for Art & Urban Resources, P.S. 1, Long Island City, NY, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Art of Reaction - The Katonah Gallery, Katonah, NY, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Approaches to Abstraction (catalogue) - University of Shanghai, China, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Paper Trail - Stephen Rosenberg Gallery, New York, NY, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Tony Martin/Paul Sierra: New Paintings - Scott Alan Gallery, New York, NY, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Abstractus: Recent Works - Scott Alan Fine Arts, New York, NY, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - The Preview Show - The Painting Center, New York, NY, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Presence and Absence - Gallery Esvandam, New York, NY, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Tony Martin: Paintings 1992-1993 - The Painting Center, New York, NY, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Painters Painting III - The Painting Center, New York, NY, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Abstract Expressionism - An Ongoing Legacy - The Gallery at Kohn Pedersen Fox, New York, NY; The Gallery at Hastings on Hudson, Hastings-on-Hudson, NY, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Tony Martin, Judith McElhone - The Painting Center, New York, NY, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Continuity and Change (catalogue) - PSA Art Showcase Public Securities Association, New York, NY, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Tony Martin: Paintings & Works on Paper - Cyr Center Gallery, Stamford, NY, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Tony Martin: November to November: A Year Of Painting - Gallery Swan, New York, NY, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - (Ap)praising Abstraction - Art Initiatives, New York, NY, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - The Good By Show - Kingsborough Community College, Brooklyn, NY, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Elizabeth Dworkin, Marilyn Giersbach-Schleife, Tony Martin - The Painting Center, New York, NY, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Art Actual, Aula De Lletres, Barcelona, Spain, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Tony Martin: New Work & Selections Spanning a Decade (catalogue) - Catherine Kessedjian, The Hague, Netherlands, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Tony Martin: Paintings - Simon Gallery, Morristown, NJ, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - New Tide: Dutch & American Painters (catalogue) - Williamsburg Art & Historical Center, Brooklyn, NY; De Nederlandsche Bank, Amsterdam, The Netherlands, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Looking for the Light - The Gallery on Hudson, Irvington, NY, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - (Four person exhibition) - 76 Varick, New York, NY, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - The Power of Drawing - Westbeth Gallery, New York, NY, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - The Inaugural Salon - Winter 1999 - Splendid, Brooklyn, NY (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Altitude: A Group Exhibition Organized by Fran Kornfeld - Gallery Onetwentyeight, New York, NY, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Painting Abstraction II - New York Studio School, New York, NY, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Brooklyn! (catalogue) - Palm Beach Institute of Contemporary Art, Palm Beach FL, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Tony Martin ~ Bendel Hydes - Studio 18 Gallery, New York, NY, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 33.5)
    - Beta Launch - Eyebeam Atelier, New York, NY, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Peace - Sideshow Gallery, Brooklyn, NY, [2002-2003] (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Flow: From the Bottom Up - Studio 18 Gallery, New York, NY, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Electronic Arts Intermix, Artists' Web Projects Launch - New York, NY, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - 2003 Year End Exhibit - Studio 18 Gallery, New York, NY (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - 179th Annual Invitational Exhibition - National Academy Invitational, National Academy Museum, New York, NY, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Galaxy - James Madison University, Sawhill Gallery, Harrisburg, VA ***see also*** Box 1, Folder 37 ***see also*** Oversize, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - 13th Anniversary Show - The Painting Center, New York, NY, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - To Shanghai and Back - Leubsdorf Art Gallery at Hunter College, New York, NY, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Subseries B: Visual Compositions, Performances & Lectures
    Mostly made up of announcements and posters advertising Tony Martin's innovative lighting- and music-integrated performances. The subseries also contains some slides, drawings and negatives pertaining to the visual compositions. The material is arranged chronologically.
    - Visual Compositions - S. F. Conservatory of Music Sonic Series and San Francisco Tape Music Center, San Francisco, CA, 1960-1967 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - An Evening of Improvisation Operas - San Francisco Conservatory of Music, San Francisco, CA, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Multiple projection score and film for Desert Ambulance by Ramon Sender - San Francisco Tape Music Center, San Francisco, CA, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Film for Play! #1 - collaboration with Morton Subotnick, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Multiple projection score and film for Mandolin by Morton Subotnick, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - After General Booth Enters Into Heaven - San Francisco Tape Music Center, San Francisco, CA, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - George Washington Slept Here I & II (with Pauline Oliveros) - San Francisco Tape Music Center, San Francisco, CA, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Light score and performance for Terry Riley in C - San Francisco Tape Music Center, San Francisco, CA, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - In the Garden (with Ramon Sender) - Berkeley, CA, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - "The Room" - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, Los Angeles, CA, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - A concert of compositions for tape and projection by Morton Subotnick, Ramon Sender and Anthony Martin - The University of British Columbia, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - "Music-Theatre-Light," An Evening with Pauline Oliveros and Anthony Martin - University of Illinois School of Music, IL, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - The Electric Ear series - The Electric Circus, St. Marks Place, New York, NY, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Light Cook (with Bill Sward), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Spectral Time, Tidal - Annual Avant Garde Festival of New York, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Charlotte (performed by and composed for Charlotte Moorman) - Annual Avant Garde Festival of New York, NY, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Spectral Time, Tide - York University, Toronto, Canada, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Interactive sound/light environment with David Tudor - Merce Cunningham and Dance Company, New York, NY, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Light Pendulum - Artist's Studio, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Vector Image Wall and works on paper: Continuously changing electronic drawing (electronic system and video projection) - Institute for Art & Urban Resources, P.S. 1, Long Island City, NY ***see also*** Oversize, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - San Francisco Tape Music Center Retrospective: Works of 1963-66 - Victoria Theater, San Francisco, CA, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - New Year Ensemble - Williamsburg Art & Historical Center, Brooklyn, NY, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Retrospective for works performed in collaboration with composers of the San Francisco Tape Music Center, and more recent video projection piece - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, Los Angeles, CA, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - "Tools for the Spirit": A talk on the artist's work and influences - New York Studio School of Drawing, Painting and Sculture, New York, NY, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Over Under Across, video projection installation - Eyebeam, Beta Launch N.Y.C., New York, NY, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Visual Poetry in Light in Time, three works for projection - Sideshow Gallery, Brooklyn, NY, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Light Marks Converse for computer and video projection; Sidewinder with Morton Subotnick liquid projection, painting in time - Cal Arts Theater at Disney Center, Los Angeles, CA, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Mode Records release Sidewinder with Morton Subotnick; March 2004 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Interpretation Series Concert - Merkin Hall, New York, NY, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Wow and Flutter - Compositions for light, with composers of the San Francisco Tape Music Center, 1963-67 - EMPAC at RPI, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Legendary Light Shows - Rotterdam Film Festival, Rotterdam, The Netherlands, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Anthony Martin, Visual Composer - Songlines Series, Center for Contemporary Music, Mills College, Oakland, CA, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Miscellaneous slides depicting light projection compositions, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Spectral Created Sound (photographs) (Box 1, Folder 75.5)
  - Subseries C: Interactive Sculptures